## Russell E. Harmon

Contact Information Rochester Institute of Technology PO Box 92423

russell.harmon.name Rochester, NY 14692 russell@harmon.name

OBJECTIVE

I am looking for a three month internship to begin June.

Summary

I am a person who loves to tinker. I spend the majority of my free time working on personal projects. Some of the projects I have independently worked on include the Linux kernel and the Gentoo Linux distribution. As a result, I've found that I have become very good at picking up new ideas quickly, and expanding what I already know with little more than the internet and a direction.

EDUCATION

Rochester Institute of Technology - Rochester, NY

September 2006 - Present

(585) 210-3330

• Major: B.S./M.S. Computer Science

• M.S. GPA: 3.0 • Minor: Music

• Expected graduation: December 2012

EXPERIENCE

Apple Inc - Cupertino, CA

Engineering Intern

6/1/2010 - 11/16/2010 http://www.apple.com/

Worked on the "Platform Kernel" team in the Core OS department at Apple. The majority of my work entailed work on libC, and on XNU (the Mac OS X kernel). My two major projects were (a) migrating code out of the kernel into userspace to take advantage of ASLR and (b) creation of an automated testing suite to test Mac OS X's power management on Intel processors. The ASLR work involved a great deal of collaboration between several different teams within Apple.

Gentoo Linux - Gentoo Foundation

Package Maintainer

August 2007 - August 2010 http://www.gentoo.org/

Maintainer of several ebuilds. An ebuild is a bash script which fetches, unpacks, compiles and installs a piece of software.

SafeNet Inc - Belcamp, MD

Engineering Intern

June 2008 - June 2010http://www.safenet-inc.com/

Worked on the SafeNet Management Console (SMC) on a team of 7. SMC is a web application built on Java, JBoss, Hibernate and JSF which manages high speed network encryption devices that SafeNet manufactures, including top-secret devices. Responsibilities included (a) creating requirements documents, (b) implementing requirements (IPv6, file synchronization), (c) testing and (d) fixing defects. Some of the specific tasks that were assigned while working there included transparent file synchronization between machines, implementing IPv6 support and implementing support for multiple SMC servers managing the same device (distributed devices).

CERTIFICATIONS

TECHNICAL SKILLS & Fluent Languages (a) C (b) Java (c) ZSH (d) BASH

Operating Systems (a) Linux [programming & administration] (b) Mac OS X [kernel programming] Server Administration (a) LDAP (b) Kerberos (c) BIND (d) DHCPD (e) MediaWiki (f) Apache Networking (a) TCP/UDP (b) IPv4, IPv6 (c) DNS (d) DHCP (e) IPSec (f) SSL (g) X.509

Tools (a) Make (b) Autotools (c) CMake (d) LLVM (e) Regex (f) LATEX **Certifications** (a) Cisco Academy, with honors (terms 1 and 2) (b) A+

EXTRACURRICULAR

CSH (Computer Science House) - Network Administrator Clubs & Activities US FIRST Robotics Team 1230 - Lead programmer

http://www.csh.rit.edu/ http://www.usfirst.org/ http://www.rockingtheboat.org/

Honors & Awards

NYC Regional Robotics Award winner - 27th place nationally Visual Basic programming award for academic excellence 2005

Rocking the Boat - Built a boat for children from the South Bronx

Special ACCOMPLISHMENTS At age 8, built my first computer. At age 10, worked my first job at City Island Computer Services. At age 12, attended my first programming class at Lehman College.